Guide to the Department of Spanish and Portuguese, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Spanish and Portuguese, Yale University, records
1920-1977
RU 247
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
(2 boxes)
The records consist of administrative and historical files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Spanish and Portuguese. Included are records of the department Advisory Committee.
Yale University. Dept. of Spanish and Portuguese
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative and historical files documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Spanish and Portuguese. Included are records of the department Advisory Committee.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Portuguese language -- Study and teaching; Spanish language -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Dept. of Spanish and Portuguese
- Records, circa 1920-1969; Accession 1980-A-007
  Conditions Governing Access
  Correspondence and exams are restricted until January 1, 2039 as established by http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives"> Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Scrapbook on department history (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    Correspondence is restricted until January 1, 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Letters of Application to Prof. Bergin, 1947-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
    - Office Correspondence, 1929-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Prof. Batchelor, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - Giovanni Previtali, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Freshman Office, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - General Office Business, 1937-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Henri Peyre, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Prof. Bergin, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Jorge Buendia, 1947-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Exams, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 16)
    Exams are restricted until January 1, 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Budget, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pamphlets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- J. L. Sammon's records of the Advisory Committee for the Department of Spanish and Portuguese, 1974-1977; Accession 1995-A-047
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2053.
  - J. L. Sammon's records of the Advisory Committee for the Department of Spanish and Portuguese, 1974-1977 (Box 1)